<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>CS 3420: Embedded Systems on Jiming Chen</title>
    <link>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CS 3420: Embedded Systems on Jiming Chen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.8</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 13:31:35 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 20: Scheduling</title>
      <link>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 13:31:35 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A &lt;em&gt;scheduling algorithm&lt;/em&gt; is a strategy used to pick a ready task for execution. A round robin scheduler has the ability to stop a process in the middle of execution, so it is a &lt;em&gt;non-preemptive&lt;/em&gt; scheduler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way we can judge a scheduler is by its average response time, in which we want to minimize the average tmie that a job waits in the ready queue before it gets scheduled.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 16: Readers and Writers</title>
      <link>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 13:30:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;concurrency-recap&#34;&gt;Concurrency Recap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, we have been discussing concurrency, whether that be multiple programs on the same CPU or multiple processors accessing the same memory. We studied mutual exclusion, specifically using locks (which ensure that no two programs enter their critical sections at the same time).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We studied how atomicity ensures only one programming is running at once, but that is a very strong requirement. Concurrency means only one critical section is running at any given time though we can still have other interleaving.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 14: Locks</title>
      <link>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture14/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 13:32:29 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dekker&amp;rsquo;s algorithm correctly implements mutual exclusion. However, this is a little bit convoluted. Additionally, each process must know about the other process, which violates modularity for programming. Therefore, we create a new abstraction: &lt;em&gt;locks&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say we have a lock called &lt;code&gt;l&lt;/code&gt;. Then, we can acquire the lock (&lt;code&gt;lock(l)&lt;/code&gt;) or release the lock (&lt;code&gt;unlock(l)&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, a program consists of the &lt;code&gt;NCS&lt;/code&gt; then a &lt;code&gt;lock&lt;/code&gt; then &lt;code&gt;CS&lt;/code&gt; then &lt;code&gt;unlock&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that using a single lock for different resources that need to be protected with a lock can be inefficient. Therefore, if multiple resources can change &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt;, we can assign a lock to &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 13: Mutual Exclusion (MUTEX)</title>
      <link>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 13:30:49 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are two ways of thinking about concurrency control: atomic actions vs. mutual exclusion. The latter is more fine-grained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atomicity means that nothing else can happen at the same time. Imagine we had a one-lane bridge. If you were trying to cross the bridge, being atomic would mean stopping all cars in Ithaca so that you can safely cross. This is a very strong statement about the system and is overkill.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 12: Concurrency</title>
      <link>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 13:50:07 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine a bitstream controlling some LEDs. If you have an interrupt in the middle of a bitstream (not aligned with the 24 bits that encode the color), then things will go wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we wanted blue light to travel down an LED strip faster than a red light, instead of using one loop, we should use two. But if we run two loops together, we can get weird bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we want two pieces of code to interact in the same memory space, we call them threads (as opposed to processes). This also means we have to be more careful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 11: Time Sharing</title>
      <link>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 13:30:20 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;context-switching&#34;&gt;Context Switching&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you open task manager, you will see hundreds of processes running all running at the same time. There is the illusion that there is a CPU dedicated to each program, but in reality, all of them have to time share on a single CPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to do this, we need to stop programs and switch very quickly. We refer to running programs as &lt;em&gt;processes&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does the CPU need to execute a program the same way at two different times? We would need at least&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 10: More Communication Protocols</title>
      <link>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 13:29:47 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;i2c-bus&#34;&gt;I2C Bus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In CAN, we worried about clock synchronization. This is not an issue with I2C because I2C has separate data (SDA) and clock (SCL) lines. The data set set when SCL is low. Conventionally, when SCL is high, the data should not change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The master signals the start of a message by changing SDA from high to low while SCL is high. Conversely, a stop is indicated by changing SDA from low to high while SCL is high.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 9: Communication Protocols</title>
      <link>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture09/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 13:37:25 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture09/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;isr-recap&#34;&gt;ISR Recap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall that ISRs are like functions, and the processor is hardwired to execute ISR and return. This includes pushing the context onto the stack (everything needed to resume execution as if nothing happened).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two types of interrupts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-maskable interrupts cannot be disabled, such as resets or HardFaults.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maskable interrupts are the most common. These are controlled by the user and can be selectively activated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, recall that in our case, we need to enable interrupts, which requires several things:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 8: Interrupts and Exceptions</title>
      <link>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture08/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 13:33:09 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture08/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say your embedded device has some buttons, which are ways the user can interract with the program. We want the user to be able to respond appropriately in all situations. For example, if a user presses two buttons at once, the program should not crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way to know if a button pressed is &lt;em&gt;polling&lt;/em&gt;, where a loop continually reads the GPIO port.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another option is to have an interrupt, in which the main code causes the program counter to move to another chunk of code called an &lt;em&gt;interrupt service routine&lt;/em&gt; (ISR) and go back to the main code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 7: Peripherals and GPIO</title>
      <link>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture07/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 13:29:15 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture07/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So far, we have used the OpenSDA USB which connects to an ARM debugging chip which is serially connected to the KL46Z256. This can interface with the red LED. We can also interface with a segment LCD, magnetometer, and accelerometer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chip has a lot of pins surrounding it, and it is isometric, so we can match the dot on the diagram with a dimple on the chip. Note that some pins are labeled similarly, e.g. PT means port.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 6: Function Calls and Program Memory Layout</title>
      <link>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture06/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 13:27:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;function-calls&#34;&gt;Function Calls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we want to implement &lt;code&gt;POP {R4}&lt;/code&gt;, we first store the value in the stack pointer to &lt;code&gt;R4&lt;/code&gt; then increment the stack pointer by 4 because the stack grows down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can also do &lt;code&gt;POP {PC}&lt;/code&gt;, which is equivalent to &lt;code&gt;POP {Rx}&lt;/code&gt; followed by &lt;code&gt;BX Rx&lt;/code&gt;. We can&amp;rsquo;t do &lt;code&gt;POP LR&lt;/code&gt; because &lt;code&gt;LR&lt;/code&gt; is not a lower register.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;push-encoding&#34;&gt;PUSH Encoding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the PUSH encoding, we encode a list of registers using a one-hot encoding to save instructions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 5: C</title>
      <link>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture05/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 13:29:39 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The C program build tool flow includes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;source files (.c, .h) which are compiled into object files (.o)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;assmebly files (.s) which are assembled into object files (.o)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;library files (.lib)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these are linked into memory into an executable file (.exe, .axf).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;assembly-files&#34;&gt;Assembly Files&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In assembly files, sections of (binary) instructions can be referred to using memory addresses which, in the assembly file, are called labels. In the assembled object file, the main memory locations point to each label in the assembly file.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 4: ARM Memory Organization</title>
      <link>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture04/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 13:31:55 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;arm-memory-map&#34;&gt;ARM Memory Map&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All versions of ARM have the same memory encoding which makes compatibility easy. Each memory address is 32 bits, which means we can have 4 gigabytes of data (because each memory block holds 1 byte).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture04/map.png&#34; alt=&#34;Cortex M0&amp;#43; Memory Map&#34; width=&#34;80%&#34; class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Fig. 1. Memory map for Cortex M0+.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bottom 500 megabytes of memory holds the code, some of which non-volatile (256 kB), meaning if the system reboots, the memory remains.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 3: Some ARM Instructions</title>
      <link>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture03/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 13:27:56 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;arm-isa-recap&#34;&gt;ARM ISA Recap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall that the ARM ISA has most instructions as 16 bits; since we have resource constraints and everything costs money, we want to fit as many instructions on the chip as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some examples of instructions are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;MOV 47, #4&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;SUB R2, R2, R4&lt;/code&gt; which is the same as &lt;code&gt;SUB R2, R4&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ADDS R2, R2, #3&lt;/code&gt; which has the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; suffix and updates the status flag&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question&lt;/strong&gt;: Which instruction(s) are not allowed to be compiled?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lecture 2: Assembly Language Overview and Intro to ARM ISA</title>
      <link>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture02/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 13:23:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;assembly-intro&#34;&gt;Assembly Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assembly code is a slightly more readable version of machine code. Machine code is a list of binary instructions that are executed by the processor. In programming languages, keywords, braces, etc. make programs understandable by humans and easy to use. Compilers take that code and convert it into assembly code. Then, each line of assembly is converted in machine code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jiming-chen.github.io/courses/cs3420/lecture02/layers.png&#34; alt=&#34;Code translation&#34; width=&#34;80%&#34; class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Fig. 1. One line of C code often corresponds to three or four lines of assembly code. Assembly to machine is just decoding, which is a very thin layer of abstraction.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why are keywords in assembly very short (two or three letters)? Back when programs were written on punched cards, there was a margin on the cards, and people wrote short descriptions for what the holes (binary representation) meant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
